[Music]
okay happy Sabbath
everyone how are you doing so far have
you been
blessed amen amen all right well uh for
the sake of time now some of you said
that you have seen uh this uh or heard
this presentation before and um I just
want to warn you that this is not the 38
minute version if any of you happen to
see that uh if you didn't happen to see
that don't worry about what I'm talking
about um let's just have a quick word of
prayer and we're going to uh open the
word of God and see some amazing things
amen let's pray Heavenly Father we ask
that you would please speak to us today
Lord uh feed us with the bread of life
and Lord May our hearts be moved as we
look into your wondrous Plan of
Salvation in Jesus name we pray
amen we are told uh in the book uh Last
Day
Events we're told in a book last day
event that um under the outpouring of
the holy spirit in the latter days
thousands will be converted in a
day uh the same number that were
converted that were baptized on the day
of Pentecost we are told we will see
conversions like that and we will see
them happen with a rapidity that will be
breathtaking so my question for you is
how many of you are looking forward to
that time when thousands will be
converted in a day amen that will be a
powerful time because the spirit of God
will be upon God's people there we are
thousands in the 11th Hour will see and
acknowledge the truth these conversions
to truth will be made with a rapidity
that will surprise the church and God's
name alone will be glorified amen amen
so uh uh uh this is good news but it
also presents a very serious challenge
because when we reason this through if
thousands will be converted in a day the
question is what are they going to be
converted to we know that they're going
to be converted to the preaching of the
Three Angels messages what is the Three
Angels messages all about call it out
for me just give me some answers
judgement The Three Angels messages is
about judgment what else it's about
worship what
else Last Day Events uh what else
salvation come on help help me out here
is is uh the Sabbath included in that
yeah yeah how about uh the mark of the
beast is it included in that how about
the 23 100 day prophecy is included in
that how about the 1260 day prophecy the
70E prophecy how about the fall of
Lucifer from Heaven yes how about the
sanctuary message yes well beloved
listen to me listen very carefully if
thousands will be converted in a day to
the preaching of the Three Angels
messages that seems to indicate beloved
that you and I must be able to share
that whole thing in a day don't pass
out whoa I wasn't expecting that one yes
beloved if if these are to be converted
in a day remember Peter preached one
message and 3,000 were
converted and so the question is how in
the world can I uh get to the place
where I can preach the Three Angels
messages in one day is it possible to
actually give our entire message the
entire Three Angels messages the entire
Plan of Salvation is it possible to do
that in just one day I want to suggest
to you that the answer is yes we're
about to do it in about an hour and 15
minutes we are going to cover the 2300
day prophecy the 1260 day prophecy the
70E prophecy the fall of Lucifer from
Heaven we're going to cover the
sanctuary message we're going to cover
the Three Angels messages fear God and
give glory to him we're going to cover
the Millennium we're going to cover the
second coming we're going to cover the
end of the wicked and Earth made new all
in about an hour and some
change are you
excited all right so um let me ask you a
question and I always set this message
up with this question how many of you
think that um if I ask you to come up
here and
explain um the last movie that you saw
now I know that 7-Day Adventist so you
don't watch TV anymore but the last
movie that you saw you think you could
come up here and explain it in about 20
minutes or so how many of you think you
could do that come on come on come on
come on guys come on seriously how many
of you think you could you could explain
a movie that you had seen whether it was
a documentary or whatever it happened to
be you could explain that movie yeah
okay now if I were to ask you to come up
here and explain to us the
Bible in about you know half an hour or
so how many of you think you could do
it okay this is what we're going to do
listen there there is something very
important about the the analogy I just
gave you and here it
is the reason that we can remember a
movie so much is because of the
images that have been placed in our
minds right a picture is worth what a
th000 words so here's what we're going
to do we're simply going to take images
from the Bible do you know what a movie
is by the way moving pictures moving
pictures it's just a bunch of pictures
put together and as you go through them
in with rapidity it forms a
movie so I have entitled this message
the blueprint it's subtitled Earth's
final
movie are you with me so what we're
about to see beloved is we're about to
watch a movie amen amen now um how many
of you how many of you have ever Juiced
before you know what that is right when
you take a a you know fruit or vegetable
and you you know maybe you get like 20
carrots and you juice it down into one
cup that's what we're going to do with
the Bible okay we're going to juice the
entire Bible so that we can cover it
we're going to span the entire great
controversy and we're going to do it in
such a way that by the grace of God you
will be able to share this message with
your friends and your neighbors and your
family how does that
sound are you ready all right so we are
going to begin and I'm going to invite
you to use your mind as the screen you
will hear me often say in this
presentation are you with me in your
movie and just simply tell me if you are
just say amen are you with me all right
our movie begins have we
prayed let's pray again Heavenly Father
please guide us give us understanding
teach us Lord we pray in Jesus name amen
all right so our movie
begins with an Angel by the name of
Lucifer now we understand that heaven
was a place of perfect peace and Perfect
Harmony
and uh uh all was in harmony to the will
of God in Ezekiel chapter 28 we read
about an angel named Lucifer but he is
also called the anointed cherub let's
read that thou art the anointed cherub
that what coverthe set thee Soul thou
was upon the holy mountain of God thou H
has walked up and down in the midst of
the stones of fire thou was perfect in
thy ways from the day that thou was
created until what iniquity was found in
thee now before we go any further we
want to establish a certain point here
Lucifer is called a covering what cherub
now in order to understand what a
covering cherub is we would have to go
uh uh uh go to the Old Testament where
God had given Moses instruction about
building something called a sanctuary
want you to see what the Bible says here
the Bible tells us uh uh speaking about
this Sanctuary that it was the example
and sh shadow of heavenly things as
Moses was admonished of God when he was
about to make the Tabernacle foree
sayith he that thou maketh all things
according to the pattern show to thee in
the mouth so very simply what this is uh
showing us is that the Old Testament
Sanctuary was a pattern or a shadow of
what Heavenly things okay so when we go
to that Old Testament Sanctuary by the
way there's a picture of the Tabernacle
how many of you have seen a picture of
the this Tabernacle before okay there's
a picture of the Tabernacle and we just
want to for the sake of time we're going
to go right into a place called The Most
Holy place now who can tell me what was
in the most holy place the Ark of the
Covenant and on either side of the Ark
of the Covenant there were two angels
and these Angels were called what
covering Angels or covering cherubs
listen to what the Bible says here Thou
shalt make a mercy seed of pure gold
gold and thou shalt make two cherubs of
gold of beaten Works shalt thou make
them in the two ends of the mercy seat
and the cherubs shall stretch forth
their wings on high doing what covering
the mercy seat with their wings now uh
we're going to take a picture look here
at a picture of that Ark very close up
here you have The Mercy Seat okay and
then here you had what was called the
Ark of the Covenant now let me ask you a
question if this picture is a symbol or
shadow of heavenly things then what do
you think that Mercy Seat
represents God's what God's Throne or
God's Dominion all right so here we have
the Throne of God and by the way in the
Old Testament Sanctuary the shakina
glory sat right on that Mercy Seat who
is a sh kind of Glory it's God okay so
we have God on the mercy seat or his
throne and then the the what was holding
up The Mercy
Seat the Ark of the Covenant if my light
will work here there we go the Ark of
the Covenant now question what was in
the Ark of the Covenant the law of God
the Ten Commandments what does that tell
us beloved that the foundation of God's
throne
in heaven was his what law are you with
me so far in your movie amen that's
scene number one the foundation of God's
Throne was his law and now if Lucifer
was a covering cherub that would mean
that Lucifer's original position in
heaven was one of the angels that stood
closest in the presence of who God very
good are you with me so far amen all
right now the Bible tells us that Lu
Lucifer was a covering cherub who knows
what the word cover means when you cover
something what are you
doing you are what you are protecting it
so what was Lucifer's job in
heaven to protect the law of God
H now beloved this is very important to
understand because most Christians do
not understand what the great
controversy is over
they don't understand what the battle is
over and and and it's kind of
frustrating when you don't understand if
you don't understand what a battle is
over then you might be fighting on the
wrong side without even realizing it
okay so what we want to see here is that
Lucifer's job was a covering cherub an
angel that was to defend and protect the
law of God which is the foundation of
his government and his throne does that
make sense you know if a throne doesn't
have law then what what do you have
Anarchy now let's see what happens here
the Bible tells
us the Bible says we read this before
Ezekiel 28 uh4 and onward Thou Art the
anointed cherub that cover and I have
set thee so thou was what perfect now
why do you think Lucifer was
perfect God created him but why else was
he
perfect because
not only did he
protect the law of God but he kept the
law of God does that make sense in other
words you don't protect something that
you're not willing to to
keep but the Bible says that Lucifer was
perfect in his ways from the day that he
was created until what iniquity was
found in thee now somebody help me out
what is Iniquity
sin what is the definition of sin
according to 1 John
3:4 transgression of the law so get this
then Lucifer sinned or transgressed a
what law now how many of you want to
take a wild guess as to what law it was
that Lucifer must have
transgressed the very law that he had
been commissioned to what defend and
protect are you with me so watch this
then beloved when Lucifer sins in heaven
it brings about a war in heaven yes yes
so here's what we begin to understand
that the very first war the war that set
off all wars was over the law of
God so if the first law was O if the
first war was over the law of God what
do you think the final war is going to
be
over are you with me in your movie so
far all right so uh so far so good the
Bible says they have filled the midst of
thee with violence and thou has sinned
uh the Bible goes on to say
here all right we've read that verse
already now we need to to to to ask
ourselves another question uh to advance
us in our in our movie so far okay the
question is we we understand from the
Bible that onethird of the Angels were
cast out of heaven with Lucifer when he
started this Rebellion our question now
is to figure out how it is that the
devil was able to cast out one or was
able to deceive onethird of intelligent
Angels now how many of you said if I was
in heaven I wouldn't have been
deceived here is a question how is it
that Lucifer was able to to deceive one3
of the Angels the answer is an amazing
one we're told here in Isaiah 14: 12-4
how art thou fallen from Heaven oh
Lucifer son of the morning how art thou
cut down to the ground which did weaken
the Nations for thou H has said in thine
heart where did he say it in his heart I
will Ascend into heaven I will exalt my
throne above the stars of God I will sit
also upon the Mount of the congregation
in the sides of the north now let me ask
you something what congregation was
Lucifer trying to exalt himself over
Congregation of angels because this is
happening where in Heaven All right so
it says here uh uh uh I will uh Ascend I
will sit on the Mount of the
congregation by the way what did Lucifer
end up doing to the
congregation he split
it do you know the first church
split happened in heaven and what was it
over the law of God
look at what it says I will Ascend above
the heights of the clouds I will be like
the most high now this is absolutely
amazing what is the most high like the
most high is
loving is kind is righteous is Holy so
let's put this together what was the
argument that Lucifer used to deceive
intelligent Angels here's what he
said we don't need a law
in order to be holy like
God okay we'll try that again I'll try
it over here maybe you guys we don't
need a law in order to be holy like
God in other words it was an argument of
self
righteousness I don't need God to tell
me how to be holy I don't need a law to
tell me how to be righteous I am already
holy I don't need to obey God's
Commandments he doesn't have the market
on righteousness we are already
holy it was an argument of
self-righteousness so Lucifer did not
say to the angels hey Angels would you
like to be
evil how many angels would have gone for
that evil H destroy heaven
and no that wouldn't have been deception
Lucifer's argument was look we don't
need God telling us
how to be
righteous I want you to imagine the
depth of this
deception um do we have any Democrats in
here don't raise your hand
please please don't do that here's why I
don't want you to raise your hands
because Republicans do we have any
Republicans in here Republicans go ahead
raise your
hand yeah you know Republicans you know
that the Democrats
are they're just being worked by Satan
we know that right
yeah all right Republicans Democrats you
know I was just kidding right we know
that it's the Republicans that is just
destroying America we know that right
yeah yeah
we it isn't it amazing how both
Republicans and Democrats think that
they're doing what's best for the
country so I want you to imagine the
kind of of of politicking that was going
on in heaven Lucifer was a politician
saying listen God's government and his
ways need
reforming he wanted to change what word
change the government of God he wanted
to do away with the law of God and here
was his argument please don't Stone me
his argument was
this too much big government
we don't need God telling us every area
what we need what we're going to do and
how we're going to we don't need God
telling us intruding in every area of
Our Lives that was his
argument let us be the rugged let us do
our own
thing
self-sufficiency wow I heard that where
have you heard that before right so
beloved I want you to understand that
the Angels didn't say oh let's just go
be evil they were at first even Lucifer
himself didn't realize what he was doing
now he is obviously evil but at then he
was genuinely thinking I can be
righteous without God now let me ask you
a question have you heard that argument
anywhere here on planet Earth before
that we don't need a law in order to be
like God we don't need a law in order to
be like Christ we can be holy and
righteous without God telling us how to
do it have you ever heard that before
it's an argument that was born out of
the heart and mouth of Satan
himself are you with me in your movie so
far all right so what happens the Bible
tells us that there is what war in
heaven and the devil and his angels are
cast out now uh we need to ask ourselves
a question why is it that God that God
did not immediately judge or destroy
Lucifer and his angels have you ever
asked yourself that question all right
so here's what we're going to find out
the answer is a profound one it's found
in Deuteronomy 19: 16 and 17 here's what
the Bible says God is laying out a
principle and uh he's speaking to Moses
and here's what it says if a false
witness rise up against any man to
testify against him that which is wrong
then both the men between whom the
controversy is shall stand before the
Lord before the priests and the judges
which shall be in those days and the
judges shall make diligent Inquisition
now basically what it was telling us
here is that whenever controversy arose
between two people there had to be a
third party are you with me so far you
know if you have an issue with someone
and you try to take that person to court
and you go to court and you know you're
going to win that case and then uh when
they say all right the judge is walking
in the judge happens to be the guy
you're taking to
court what do you
know there's no way you're going to win
this trial right so think about let's
take this principle it's a very fair
principle in heaven how many sides were
there to the Rebellion two two God and
His angels the devil and his angels
where is the third party there is no
third
party do you see the
Dilemma do you see the Dilemma are you
with me in your movie so far am you guys
are glued to the screens amen
all right so so what is God going to do
how is what what is the in fact here's
something interesting the Bible tells us
in Ezekiel 28:17 as Lucifer's being cast
out of Heaven Ezekiel 28 17 says
something interesting it says thine
heart was lifted up because of thy
Beauty thou has corrupted thy wisdom by
reason of thy brightness I will cast
thee to the ground I will lay thee
before kings that they may behold thee
very interesting phrase I will lay you
before Kings the term appears to be
synonymous with some kind of judgment
like God was saying to Lucifer I'm going
to lay you before a group of kings that
are going to judge
you the question is who would those
kings
be are you with me in your movie so far
I want you to notice what the Bible says
Revelation 1: 15 and6 and from Jesus
Christ who is a faithful witness and the
first begotten of the dead and the
prince of the kings of the earth unto
him that loved us and washed us from his
own from our sins in his own blood and
has made us what Kings and Priests unto
God and to his father so guess what
beloved who would be those kings who
would be that third party that judges
Lucifer
us wow am what a high calling amen what
I what I what I like to say beloved is
that is that you are God's jewelry
amen
amen you are his
jewelry beloved let me can I warn you
some can I don't skip jury
duty that will not be a good thing if
you skip jury duty by the way only
jurors will be
saved we'll come back to that we'll come
back to that listen
uh uh um the Bible tells us in 1
Corinthians 6: 2 and3 do you not know
that the what Saints shall do what judge
the world and if the world shall be
judged by you are you unworthy to judge
the smallest matters know you not that
we shall judge angels are you with me so
far are you with me in the movie do you
see this is it making sense so far amen
very good so we when God created Adam
and Eve they were to serve as the jurors
they were the kings in other words
Humanity was going to be the jurer in
fact when God created Adam and Eve what
did he give them he gave them Dominion
who has Dominion but a king watch this
when jurors are selected there are
usually some criteria in order to be a
juror notice criteria number one little
or no firsthand knowledge of the
crime let me ask you something where was
Humanity when Lucifer rebelled in
heaven we weren't even
created so far so good are you ready for
this one point number two a juror must
be a
law
abiding
[Applause]
citizen are you going to make me get
excited all by myself just up here alone
are you going to leave me lonely up
here so so uh H jurors must be
law-abiding citizens we know that when
God created Adam and Eve he created them
with the law of God written upon their
hearts very good okay number three a
jurer must have sound discernment
between Good and Evil
and number four they must not be swayed
by public opinion amen so Watch What
Happens Lucifer sees the creation of
Adam and Eve and he begins to wonder
okay are these huh are these the ones
that are to judge me is this the jury
that's supposed to bring me into
condemnation and you know what he does
let me ask you if you were a criminal
and you had access to the jury what
would you try to do oh yeah corrup
bribe the jury
and guess what Lucifer does just that he
comes to Eve in the garden and he says
uh the servant said unto the woman you
shall not surely die uh you know after
he asked her you know did God say you
can't eat from every every tree notice
what he says for God does know that in
the day you eat thereof then your eyes
shall be opened and ye shall be as Gods
knowing good and
evil you shall be as
Gods you shall be like God uhoh look out
does that sound familiar yeah how did he
deceive the angels in heaven we can be
like God without obeying what he says
the very same thing he didn't go to Eve
and say hey Eve would you like to be
[Applause]
[Laughter]
evil no no no no no he said eve you can
be like God now by the way the word God
is the Hebrew Elohim which means judges
Eve you want to be a really good
judge you want to really know the
difference between good and evil eat
from this tree and then you'll be a
really good
judge wow
whoa
whoa So Adam and Eve they both eat of
the fruit and what happens they lose
their status as long all abiding
citizens of the Kingdom of
Heaven Jesus comes to the garden and
what do we know that he institutes The
Plan of Salvation so now you tell me
what must what must be the purpose of
the Plan of
Salvation to restore mankind to being
law abiding citizens and sound jurors
who are able to discern between right
and
wrong guess what you now understand the
entire purpose of the Gospel praise the
Lord it is to restore us to being
citizens of the kingdom of heaven and by
the way the only way that we can be K uh
citizens of the Kingdom of Heaven is if
we are willing to be subject to Heaven's
laws you see what we're doing as we
study with our with our friends and our
neighbors is we've got to set a
foundation for them so that they can
understand the what we share them in
further studies they can understand it
in light of the big picture if they
don't see the big
picture
picture we've got to hang this in
memories Hall are you with me all right
so are you with me in your movie so far
all right now what we're going to do now
is we're going to fast forward a little
bit because God has already shown us
that he's going to come and and set a
plan in place to restore mankind okay
and we'll fast forward and we're going
to come down now to the time of Moses
God is about to use a man named Moses
he's about to take a people out of
captivity and who are those people they
are the children of Israel okay God
calls the children of Israel because
he's evidently going to use them as part
of his plan to re restore mankind to
being what sound jurors law abiding
citizens of the kingdom of heaven so
what does God do when he calls Israel
out of captivity he gives them a very
special gift what is that gift it is the
sanctuary now I want to share something
with you the Bible says here Exodus 25:8
let them make me a What sanctuary that I
may do What dwell among them listen why
is this so
important um in fact let's look at
another verse very quickly Psalm 7713
says thy what way oh God is where in the
sanctuary now pause right now um when Mo
when God came to Adam and Eve in the
garden what was the first question he
asked them Adam where where are you now
did God not know where Adam
was he knew where he was what was he
trying to get Adam to
realize that you are what
lost you are
lost because of man's Rebellion they
were put out of the garden right God's
plan is to bring
man back into his
presence so what does he do he gives
them a
map going make me get excited oh you're
G to do this aren't you aren't you he
gives them a map he gives them something
called a sanctuary which by the way is a
miniature model of God's throne room
where in heaven so the very same thing
in other words it's like God saying
listen if you want to know how my
government operates if you want to be
subject to my government in heaven I'm
going to give you a miniature model on
Earth and what I call by the way how
many of you have ever been
lost and um have you ever like you know
asked someone pull over ask someone for
directions and they're like oh yeah sure
you know you're in a strange place like
Hawaii let's say and uh you know you're
trying to get to you know I don't know
shark Cove and they're like oh yeah you
know all you need to do is just go down
the street make a right here and then a
left there and then just keep going and
ah you'll be right
there and the guy it's
nice he looks like a friendly guy and so
you trust him you you put all your
hopes
aspirations just believing that he is
right and you you go off driving and you
make the left and the right and you do
exactly what he
said and you end up someplace
else oh the frustration right have you
ever had that happen to you
oh what if we had a GPS that was just so
accurate we could know all the time oh I
am here and I know exactly where I need
to go Beloved the sanctuary is God's
GPS his gospel Plan of
Salvation you cannot get lost if you
have this
blueprint God has given it to us so that
we can know the way back to the father
amen so how do you think the devil feels
about this
blueprint oh yeah he must are you with
me in your movie so far yeah he must
hate this thing because God takes the
very thing in heaven he makes a replica
of it and sends it down to earth and the
devil's probably going look it's down
here on
Earth and then he hears God speaking to
Israel about this sanctuary and he
understands that God has given this
Sanctuary to Israel to prepare the world
for the coming of the Messiah this
Sanctuary contains
The Plan of Salvation to save the whole
world how do you think Satan feels about
that oh he's
angry and he realizes he's got to do
something but beloved before we go there
in our movie you and I need to
understand the importance of this
blueprint are you ready all right so
here we go
oh okay all right I'm sorry I just had
to get excited by myself for a moment
all right so listen to this the
sanctuary reveals the presence of God
now you'll remember that God said to
Moses let them make me a What sanctuary
that I may do What dwell among them so
as you looked at the outer tent of this
Sanctuary it was just regular covering
you know like a just a plain brown
covering nothing attractive on the
outside but on the very inside of that
Temple was the very presence of who God
do you know that the sanctuary reveals
Jesus Christ Jesus said when he came
Jesus answered and said unto them
destroy this Temple and in three days I
will do what I will raise it up then
said the Jews 40 and six years was this
temple in building will thou rear it up
in three days but he spake of the Temple
of his what body you see beloved when
Jesus came to this earth who knows what
his name was
called Behold a virgin shall be with
child and shall bring forth a son they
shall call his name what Emmanuel
meaning what God God With Us you see as
you looked at that baby nothing
spectacular just looked like a regular
baby but inside that
child was the very presence of
God are you with me all right so you're
sharing this with your friends and your
neighbors and they're going wow I never
knew that about the
sanctuary are you with me look at what
it goes on to tell
us Jesus said very very I say un to you
he that entereth not by the door of the
Sheepfold or into the Sheepfold but
climbthestacks there was something
called the altar
of
sacrifice you know what happened there
animals were sacrificed what does that
point to it points to Jesus Christ he
walks through the
door and through the door he goes to
that sacrifice so Jesus says listen to
this the Bible tells us to him the
Porter openeth and the sheep hear his
voice and he calleth his own Sheep by
name and leadth them out when he putteth
forth his own voice he goeth before them
and the Sheep do what follow him so
beloved listen if Jesus is in the
sanctuary if he walks in the sanctuary
then what will his followers be found
doing following him in that
pattern are you with
me Jesus says I am the
way but Psalm says thy way oh God is in
the s that means Jesus is in the
sanctuary
are you with me all right let's see how
else this Sanctuary points to the Plan
of Salvation now here is here are the
articles of furniture and I just need
you to help me out here most of you
should know this so help me out in the
outer court is what we call the altar of
what sacrifice and then uh if you moved
up a little bit further you would see an
article of furniture called the labor
that's where the priests would do what
wash their hands and their feet because
they were either mingled with blood or
dirt please don't lose this here okay uh
what about the uh table of showbread
this by the way was a a compartment
called the the Tabernacle proper and it
was a two compartment room divided by a
curtain okay so in the Holy place that's
the first compartment there were three
articles of furniture There was a seven
Branch Candlestick and what did that
seven Branch Candlestick what do you
think that
represents well it represents light it
represents light in fact Jesus said ye
are the light of the world a city set on
a hill cannot be hid so that seven
Branch Candlestick represents the people
of God the light of the world we are
supposed to be like a city set on a hill
are you with me what do you think the
the uh labor represents water it
represents what baptism what do you
think the altar of sacrifice represents
the death of Christ what do you think
the table of sobre repres
represents man shall not live by what
bread alone but by every word that
proceeds out of the mouth of God how
about the alar of incense altar of
incense represents prayer according to
Revelation chap uh 8: 1-3 that incense
you know how incense just Rises you burn
and it rises just like our prayers when
we pray it rises to God Amen all right
so you have the altar of incense and
then you went into the most holy place
and there you had the Ark of the the
Covenant the two angels the covering
cherubs The Mercy Seat and the Very
presence of God are you with me now I
want you to watch this
here uh we have the altar of sacrifice
we have the labor we have the table of
showbread the altar of incense the seven
Branch Candlestick and the Ark of the
Covenant now do you realize that if you
were to
trace around these articles just draw an
outline around the Articles do you know
that you would find a
cross you're really going to make me get
excited alone up
here thousands of years before Christ
would come upon the scene the sanctuary
pointed to the fact that he would die on
a cross for our
sins not only that beloved but if you
look a little bit further you will
notice that in every place that an
article of furniture is Jesus Jus was
wounded
how Jesus had was nailed in his
feet he was nailed in the left hand
nailed in the right
hand a crown of thorns on his
head he died from a broken
heart and do you know what happened when
the Roman soldiers came to him to see if
he was
dead they took a spear and pierced his
side and guess what came out water and
blood just as the
priests whose hands mingled with blood
would wash at the labor every article of
furniture points to a place in which
Christ was wounded amen what are the
odds what are the odds how about this
the
sanctuary points to the fact of who
Christ is we know beloved that
Christ is the Lamb of God are you with
me altar of what sacrifice not only is
he the Lamb of God he is the water of
life amen are you with me amen not only
is he the Water of Life beloved he is
the bread of life woo he's the bread of
life not only that beloved he is our
intercessor not only is he our
intercessor he is the light of the world
and beloved if that weren't enough he is
the law of God
personified
amen amen amen do you see how important
this blueprint
is let's do some more Christ or I'm
sorry we're going to look at the Exodus
and we're going to notice that Christ
delivers his people through this pattern
you say how Pastor listen in The Exodus
the first thing that God commanded the
children of Israel to do was
what they were to kill a lamb what
article of furniture are we looking
at the altar of sacrifice that's the
Passover you with me so far amen okay
next after the
Passover the children of Israel go and
they are confronted with the Red
Sea do do you see
this what does the Red Sea symbolize
baptism
baptism after the Red Sea is parted and
they cross over the Red Sea the Bible
says in the very next chapter chapter 16
the Bible tells us that God RS down Mana
from Heaven do you think that's a
coincidence no do you see what God is
doing here he's leading the children of
Israel through a
pattern watch this in Exodus chapter 17
or I think it's Exodus chapter 19 God
says to Israel Israel you are now my
Royal Nation my peculiar treasure my
city set on a hill he is referring them
he is referring to the seven Branch
Candlestick he is about to use Israel as
the light to the whole world amen amen
in that same chapter God tells Moses to
tell the children of Israel to take
three days to prepare themselves to meet
God what article of furniture are we
looking at the altar of
incense heart
preparation why because in Exodus
chapter 20
you thought I was making this
up Exodus chapter 20 what happens God
speaks the Commandments to his people do
you think this is coincidence no
absolutely not beloved all right we're
going to run through some more I just
want you to get this blueprint nailed
out I want this picture needs to be
hanging in memories heart are you with
me repetition deepens the impression
okay so let's look at another one let's
look at a couple more here Christ's life
this is beautiful where was Christ
born but where in
Bethlehem in a stable what's in the
stable animals Christ was born among
animals what article of furniture would
you point to to represent Christ born
among
animals the altar of sacrifice we might
say that Christ was born a living
sacrifice he was born to
die at the age of
30 what happens to
Christ he's
baptized that's the
labor question what happens after Christ
is
baptized the Bible says he is led up
into the wilderness
how many times is Christ tempted in the
wilderness how many articles of
furniture do we
have what's the first
Temptation turn this Stone into what
bread do you think the devil is aware of
this
blueprint I mean you think this is
coincidence okay watch this temptation
number two who he says throw yourself
down from this cliff and call out to God
he's trying to tempt Jesus to offer up
presumptuous prayer the altar of incense
Temptation number three he says look I
know you came for your people I know
you've come to redeem your people I'll
give you your seven Branch Candlestick
if you just Bow Down and Worship
me Jesus overcomes all three Temptations
and he goes on to preach the law of God
combined with the mercy of
God Amen are you with me in your movie
so far very good okay just please just
just let's just do a couple more let's
look at this Christ descends from Heaven
the pattern even shows Christ descent
watch
Christ left his throne in
heaven amen uh-huh yes do you see that
all right he left his throne in heaven
he lived off of the word of
God table of so bread
he let his light shine John 1:9 alter of
uh seven Branch Candlestick and he lived
a life of prayer altar of incense he was
baptized and then
crucified which way do you want
[Laughter]
it
am I just kind of like you know just
like wallowing in the
wow all right all right so uh uh how
about
this um Christ's
Ascension Christ came to this world and
died altar of
sacrifice he was resurrected and
purified labor right he enters into the
Heavenly Sanctuary
ministering among the seven Branch
candlesticks ministering he ascended to
give Mana from Heaven he ascended to
intercede on our behalf and one day in
the future we knew that Christ would
enter into the most holy place to begin
the work of
judgment amen all right all right very
good um how about this do you know that
the even the New Testament is based upon
the pattern check this out Matthew Mark
Luke and John what are they
about it's the gospel but what is it
about it's about the
life death
Matthew Mark Luke and John the four
gospels it's about the sacrifice of
Christ what's next in the Bible the book
of Acts what is the book of Acts all
about the baptism of the Holy
Spirit okay you're going to make me get
excited
alone so the book of Acts is about
baptism all right now we have Romans to
Jude what does Romans from Romans to the
book of Jude what does it talk about I
tell you it talks about the importance
of the word of God it talks about the
importance of of Christ's intercession
and prayer it talks about the importance
of letting your light
shine and then we get to the Book of
Revelation which brings you into the
very throne room of
God okay well maybe the silence is
because you're just watching a really
good movie and you don't want to be
disturbed right now so I'll leave you
alone and let's just keep watching the
movie
okay all right so um let's see here uh
uh yeah let's do one more this is very
important beloved our path if we've seen
the path in all these different ways we
we must realize that our path to the
throne of God follows the same pattern
so if I want to be saved if I want to
come to Christ what is the first thing
that I must
do I must accept the sac sacrifice of
Christ on my behalf amen that is the
first step in the path to the throne of
God now if you are are not a Christian
if you're out there in the world and and
and the devil knows that the first step
is the altar of sacrifice he's got like
10 demons right here like linebackers
trying to stop you from breaking through
to that article of
furniture do you understand what I'm
saying but let's say by the grace of God
you break through those 10 demons and
you accept Christ at the cross you
cannot go I made it it's over it's
finished I can go home
now why do you know
no because the blueprint tells us so
amen you see beloved when people don't
have a blueprint you kind of don't know
where you're going if you don't have a
GPS you kind of just guesstimate
but when you have something that shows
with Clarity the path you can know for
sure if someone says to you hey it was
all finished at the cross what can you
say to them wait a
minute I have asked friends I've done
this study with people who believe one
saved always saved or that it was all
finished at the cross and when I get
here and then they look at that and they
go no it can't be done at the
cross do you see what's happening here
when you when you get a person to
understand and accept this blueprint
it's going to obviously lead
somewhere all right so after I'm
baptized if I'm gen if I'm a genuine
Christian and I accept Christ sacrifice
what's the next thing that I must do if
I'm genuine I'm going to be baptized and
listen beloved if there were 10 demons
standing before the altar of sacrifice
and you broke through guess how many
there are standing before the the the
the labor they're
20 don't let them Advance don't let her
advance but by the grace of God you
break through and you get baptized
praise God I have accepted Christ and
I've been baptized woo it's done over
with finished I'm ready to
go I'm
good no beloved why because a genuine
Christian will be found doing what
studying the word of God Amen a genuine
Christian is going to be found praying
and interceding and accepting Christ's
intercession on their behalf a genuine
Christian is going to let his or her
light what shine so if there were 20
demons trying to stop you from baptism
then there's 60 demons trying to stop
you from studying the Bible witnessing
and
praying so question where is God
ultimately trying to lead
us
yeah do you see how obvious the pattern
is when someone says we don't need to
keep the law they're saying it because
they're giving you directions without a
blueprint and they may be genuine they
may look
nice but don't put your hopes and
aspirations in
man put it in God and God has given us a
blueprint for a reason to show us that
anyone who seeks to come through any
other way than through the
door and those who refuse to follow the
lamb in the steps that he himself walked
they're simply out to get you
lost they may not realize it but that's
what the devil's trying to do all right
so oh I love this
one do you know that we're told that
Jesus is going to come through the
Orion take a look at
that that's the
Orion I'm just going to wait
here's what's interesting this is the
Orion Nebula you know what a nebula is
it's a place
where
Stars Are
Born
okay no no no no
let's move on let's move on let's move
on all right so Israel has been
commissioned to take this blueprint into
all the world are you with me in your
movie so far what happens is that the
way I like to compare it is that God
gives Israel this blueprint like it wore
football and he says to Israel Israel
take it down the field and off Israel
goes with this blueprint right but what
happens you see Israel that God has
called and commissioned to be prepared
for the coming of the Messiah they begin
to Fumble the ball they begin to worship
idols and and and bow down before images
and they're doing all these kind of
things and they're doing it so much so
that God allows them to go into
Babylonian captivity it's like he says
time out Israel you get your
benched Penalty
Box Israel has to sit in captivity for
how
long 70 years years in Babylonian
captivity just towards the end of that
Babylonian captivity there is a prophecy
given to a Prophet by the name of Daniel
and the prophecy states that there would
be 70 weeks now let me pause here
because we're here's what we've just
done we've just gone off from Genesis
we're now in the Book of Daniel okay and
Daniel is given the first of three time
prophecies how many time prophecies
three what are those three time
prophecies they are the 70 weeks the
1260 years and the
2300 years now how many of you ever been
confused about those
prophecies kind of you know like what
are they really about well listen very
simple these three time prophecies are
really only one
prophecy do do you get that so so let me
break it down few if I can uh uh these
three prophecies are simply subsections
of a larger prophecy 70 weeks of that
prophecy deals with a certain thing 1260
years of that prophecy deals with a a
certain thing and then the 2300 years
which is the big picture deals with
something else do you have that so do
you have that so far all right so we're
going to break these three prophecies
down very quickly prophecy number one is
the 70 we prophecy
now I wanted to throw this in here
because I just want you to this is this
is beautiful the 70 weeks how many days
in a week seven so 70 * 7 would equal
490 days okay but in Bible prophecy a
day equals a year I want you to notice
what John Gil the Baptist scholar said
he said this space of 70 weeks is not to
be understood of weeks of days which is
too short for a time for the Fulfillment
of so many events as are mentioned nor
were they fulfilled within such a space
of time but of weeks of what years and
make up
490 years within which time beginning
from a date after mentioned all the
things prophesied were accomplished and
this way of Reckoning of years by days
is Not Unusual in the sacred writings so
here is a Baptist scholar laying out the
principle for a Day for year you with me
so far all right so what was to happen
in the 70E prophecy very simple God
basically said to Israel Israel you have
70 weeks or
490 years to get it together the Messiah
is coming at the end of that time if you
do not get it together by the end of the
490 years I'm going to take the
blueprint from you and I'm going to give
it to somebody
else are you with me so far
well what
happens Jesus comes on the scene by the
way this 70E prophecy covers a time span
from Babylon do you know how many
nations Rose and fall Rose and fell
before or during the 70 week prophecy
you should
know
four the prophecy was given towards the
end of what of what Empire the
Babylonian Empire meido Persia Came Upon
the scene and fell Greece Came Upon the
scene and fell and the 4 uh 93 or 490
years brings us down to the time of
Jesus which is in what Empire the Roman
Empire okay do you know that the Bible
speaks about these four Kingdoms in
Daniel chapter 7 what are those kingdoms
you remember that Babylon the lion uh M
Persia the bear Greece the leopard uh
and the that fourth Beast representing
Rome okay this is just review for us
don't don't get lost this is just review
right so the 70 the 490 years takes us
through four kingdoms and brings us down
to the time of Rome right what happens
when Jesus comes on the scene the Jews
do what they reject Jesus and in
rejecting Jesus what also did they
reject the
blueprints how they rejected the Lamb of
God yes they rejected
the Water of Life yes they rejected the
bread of life remember that give us his
flesh to eat what remember that they
rejected his prayer of forgiveness on
the cross they rejected the light of the
world they comprehended it not the Bible
says and ultimately in rejecting him
they rejected his law they rejected the
sanctuary and therefore God says okay
you don't want the sanctuary I will take
it from you and I'm going to give it to
another
people you remember what happened when
Jesus died the veil in the temple was
what RI what did that mean the Earthly
Temple was of no more what value because
Christ had now ascended or was about to
ascend into a Heavenly
Temple Israel rejects the
Messiah and God raises up a new people
who are those
people spiritual Israel
all right beloved we've just gone
through the whole Old Testament are you
with me so far you have just watched the
movie that has taken you through the
whole theme of the New Testament the
whole Old Testament was simply Satan
trying to destroy Israel and the
blueprint that they possessed that was
it so we're now at this transition where
we read you are now a chosen generation
a royal priesthood a holy nation A
peculiar people that you should show
forth the Praises of him who has called
you out of Darkness into his marvelous
life which in times past were not a
people but are now what the people of
God so Watch What Happens Israel gets
down to the 50 yard line with the
blueprint you know what they do when
Jesus comes they fumble the ball God
takes the blueprint from them and he
hands it to spiritual Israel and off
they go down the
field are you with me so
far what is their message their message
message is about a risen savior in a
Heavenly what
Temple are we good all right now let's
move on remember this who is the devil
now going to use to attack the early
church the same Kingdom
Rome Rome that the same Rome that put
Christ to death began to persecute the
early church you ever read about that
you know the Christians being thrown to
the Lions and stuff like that well guess
what happens
the more Christians die the more they
what they multiply so Satan realizes
this tactic is not working so he has to
come up with another
Power a power that rises after
Rome are you with me this power he's
going to use to attack spiritual Israel
and also attack the
Heavenly Sanctuary watch this in the
Book of Daniel The Book of Daniel speaks
of the power that Rose after Rome it
says I was considering the horns on the
the fourth Beast which represents Rome
and there was another horn a little one
that came up among them who does that
little horn represent it represents the
Church of the Dark
Ages watch this the Bible says or rather
Adam Clark who is a Methodist says this
in prophetic language a Time signifies a
year and the prophetic year has a year
for each day the three years and a half
a day standing for a year will amount to
1,260 years this is a Methodist speaking
are you with me I'm just showing you the
the how this is not an Adventist
interpretation beloved we have built
upon those that came before us us amen
are you with me all right so watch this
H uh the
1260 days is actually 1260 years and
that is the time that we are told that
this little horn would dominate or would
attack the people of God and the
sanctuary of God in fact here's what the
Bible says the Bible tells us in a few
places uh in Daniel chapter 8:12 it says
the daily sacrifice would be taken away
what article of furniture we looking at
Daily
sacrifice altar of sacrifice very good
it also says in Daniel chapter 8:12 It
cast down the truth to the ground where
can we find the truth word Thy word is
truth very good according to Daniel chap
7:2 it would wear out or persecute the
Saints of the most high what article of
furn furniture represents the Saints of
the most high the seven Branch C very
good are you are you guys following this
in other words we can know who this
power is simply by looking at how it
would
attack these truths taught by the
Heavenly Sanctuary watch
this in 2 Thessalonians chapter 2:3 and
4 the Bible says of this power that he
would show himself that he is God where
would that point
to very good
It also says in Daniel chter 7:25 that
he would think to change times and laws
where would that point to six very good
so we know what we're looking for watch
this did a power rise upon the scene
that attacked each one of these articles
the answer is a resounding yes notice
this the Roman Catholic
system replaced or cast down the truth
of Christ sacrifice
and replaced it by teaching
indulgences in other words the sacrifice
of Christ is not sufficient for the
Forgiveness of sins you have to
buy to be
forgiven beloved this was a direct
attack upon the very purpose Christ came
to die people were buying
forgiveness instead of going to Jesus
Jesus Christ not only did they attack
this truth during the Dark Ages they
also attack the truth let me read this
very quickly through the Eucharist it
says the power of the priest is the
power of the Divine person for the
transubstantiation of the bread requires
as much power as the creation of the
world thus the priest may be called the
creator of the
Creator
blemy so every time the priest raises
that piece of bread and breaks it what
he's saying is that I have the power to
crucify Christ
again beloved Christ died once for our
sins once so that truth was cast down
Not only was that truth cast down also
the truth about the baptism was cast
down as the church began to practice
what was called infant
baptism you don't need to confess and
repent we're just going to sprinkle
you you see beloved what this did was it
did away with the need for confession
and repentance and suddenly as long as
you were sprinkled as a child you're
good not only did they cast that truth
down they attacked the word of God they
replac the word of God the table of
showbread with the traditions of the
church in fact here's what they said
they said the traditions of the church
are more important than the Bible itself
they also said that you are not allowed
you as a lay person are not allowed to
possess a Bible because you can't
interpret
it only the priest can interpret
it beloved do you know
why watch this not only did they attack
these three things they also
attacked the altar of
incense Christ mediation was cast down
and replaced by something called the
confessional booth
can I tell you something about the
confessional
Booth the confessional Booth is a two
compartment room divided by a
curtain with a man sitting in the place
of
God while men come and confess
their sins before
him do you think this is
coincidence you see beloved it's all in
the
blueprint when we understand the
blueprint we will understand the entire
Plan of
Salvation listen what's next not only
did they attack these things they also
attacked the Church of God by
persecuting the Church of God sending
them into hiding and thus producing I
believe why why we call it the
Dark
Ages the way that the church
evangelized was by burning you at the
stake repent or will burn
you and then they reached up into the
most holy
place and cast down the law of God how
did they do that Daniel 7:25 says that
he would think to do what change times
and laws what commandment did the Church
change the Sabbath
Commandments what are the odds beloved
do you see how when you lay this out
when you you know if you say to someone
keep the Sabbath ah what
for but now when you give him the whole
background and show them how the
Rebellion began in heaven Lucifer trying
to change the law of God we can now see
why he's trying to do the same thing on
Earth by the way not only did they
change only change the law of
God there is the head of the church
sitting in between two terrible
you'll also notice four priests on
either side of them just like four
living creatures surrounded the Throne
of
God those
fishs man sitting in the place of
God the West ministers confession of
Faith a presbyterian document says this
there is no other head of the church but
the Lord Jesus Christ nor can the pope
of Rome in any sense be head thereof but
is that
Antichrist I thought that was only an
Adventist
thing
whoa is that Antichrist that man of Sin
and Son of predition that exalteth
himself in the church against Christ and
against all that is called
God you see Beloved the reason I like to
bring bring these into my presentation
is to show look this is not some weird
interpretation by Adventist this is this
is what protestantism taught for
hundreds of years until they lost their
protest
amen So Adam Clark a Methodist says this
in prophetic language a Time signifies a
year we read this already I'm going to
pick up to where it says here the end is
probably not very distant it has already
been grievously shaken by the French
talking about the papacy in
1798 Adam Clark a Methodist a me a what
everyone a Methodist identifies
1798 the French Republican Army under
General berier took possession of the
city of Rome and entirely superseded the
whole papal
power
wow all right so what do we have so far
we've just hit the 70E prophecy and now
we saw the 1260 year prophecy and what
where are we now in our movie we see
that Satan seems to be
winning but beloved you know in every
movie where it seems like the bad
guy we know there comes that point in
the movie where things are going to turn
in the favor of good this beloved brings
us to the final part of of the prophecy
of Daniel chapter of of the Book of
Daniel which is a 2300 day prophecy and
I want you to notice what it says it
says how long shall be the vision
concerning the daily sacrifice and the
transgression of desolation to give both
the sanctuary and the host to be trotten
underfoot in other words the angel is
asking here a question how long is this
little horn going to be able to do these
things and trample upon the truth and
the answer is unto
2,300 days then shall the sanctuary be
what everyone cleansed some translations
say
restored in other words the truths that
were cast down during the Dark Ages will
be restored by the end of the
years when does the 2300 year prophecy
end according to the prophecy
1844 so if we are right watch this if we
are right then what we're going to see
is a restoration of all those truths by
what year 1844 watch
this listen to this a Baptist Minister
John Gil listen to what John Gil said
about the 2300 day prophecy this is
mindblowing these 2300 days may be
considered so many years which will
bring it down to the end of the sixth
Millennium or
thereabout when it may be hoped there
will be a new face upon the things upon
the sanctuary and the Church of God and
a cleansing of it from all corruption in
Doctrine discipline worship and
conversation okay I I I forgot you're
watching a movie so leave you alone as
you're watching let's just continue John
Gil Baptist scholar says that the 2500
days will bring about our restoration of
Purity in Doctrine and
worship so let's
see over a period of 500 years all of
these truths began to be restored are
you ready for this this is the highlight
of the
presentation are you ready you may as
well just go ahead and get excited now
go ahead just go ahead
okay okay watch watch watch your movie
pay
attention in the
1300s a man by the name of John
whitecliffe comes upon the scene anyone
know what John White by the way John
whitecliffe is is the founder of a
movement called the
lards now John whitecliffe what did he
do he translated the Bible into the L
into the common language of the people
do you know what article of furniture
John White effectively restored the
table of showbread how many of you want
to say Amen to that now watch this do
you know that John Whitecliff how many
of you appreciate John Whitecliff do you
know that if you were living in the
1300s and someone said hey you want to
be a low Lord do you know that you would
have been considered a
cult people would have been like oh W
Cliff
whoa
hey if you decided to follow follow W
Cliff's teachings you would not probably
not be able to go home to your
neighbors your neighbors would look at
you
funny in other words beloved if you are
going to follow Whitecliff in that time
you had to be bold enough to stand for
truth praise God for John
whitecliffe in the 1400s another man is
born and by the way the as I said they
were persecuted as a cult in the 1400s a
man by the name of Martin Luther is born
and Martin Luther begins what's known as
a Protestant Reformation Martin Luther
is the founder of the Lutheran movement
and guess what Martin Luther restores he
says wait a minute we don't have to buy
forgiveness Christ's sacrifice is
sufficient for the Forgiveness of sins
amen and beloved if I was living in that
time guess what I would have been Martin
Luther but guess what do you realize
that if you were in that time and you
said hey I'm a Lutheran do you realize
that people would have looked at you as
a Cults do you know do you know what
they can if internet was around in the
days of Martin Luther woo yeah I heard
that Martin
[Laughter]
Luther you would have been considered a
cult you had to have boldness and a
desire to follow Christ if you were
going to stand with truth and by the way
uh it's interesting that when Whitecliff
had a translated the Bible it was
present truth and then when white when
Martin Luther comes along by that time
the Bible was already kind of spreading
around not fully it was still present
truth but it was almost like moving into
a little bit of precious
truth we'll come back to
that Martin Luther and the lutherans
retreated as a cult in the s or in the
same in the 1500s another man by the
name of John Calvin comes upon the scene
John Calvin is the founder of the
Presbyterian movement and John Calvin
has a very special burden for prayer
he's like we don't need to go to priests
and popes to to get forgiveness of sins
and we can pray directly to God Calvin
effectively restores what everyone the
altar of
incense now if you would have dreamed
about being a calvinist in that day
following Calvin a presbyterian I should
say you know what you would have been
treated as a cult oh by the way guess
who were the ones that would have
treated you like a cult the
Lutheran you see the lutherans when they
discovered their truth they were like
okay this is it I mean what are they to
what's he talking about what are they
talking about we have the truth we have
all there is to have Luther didn't
realize that he was fulfilling part of a
bigger
picture and in the 1600s a man by the
name of John Smith comes upon the scene
John Smith along with Roger Williams
become known as the founders of the
Baptist movement now let me ask you
something what did the Baptist focus
upon baptism baptism now can you imagine
in that time you know if you started
talking about baptism by immersion
people would have been like oh you're
crazy you are a cult don't you know
everyone
sprinkles you would have been treated by
like a cult and guess who would have
been treating you as a
cult the lutherans and the
Presbyterians they became friends ah
those Baptist man let's get
them are you seeing a pattern here
amen
huh so the Baptist restor that truth of
baptism by immersion and by the way
people may have been like you Baptists
are just focused on
baptism you know what beloved it was
present Truth for that time God had
given them a present truth and people
who didn't understand they accused them
of just focusing on one thing no God had
called them into existence for that one
reason praise God for the
Baptist in the
1700s a man by the name of John Wesley
comes upon the scene John Wesley Wesley
is the founder of the Methodist
movement I think somebody knows where
this is
going John Wesley has a very special ver
burden he believes that every individual
is an
evangelist everybody's supposed to be a
light to the world and he begins these
missionary societies and he's sending
people out to evangelize uh John Wesley
effectively H restores the seven Branch
Candlestick if you considered being a
Methodist in the 1700s
and guess who was persecuting you the
Baptists the Presbyterians and the
lutherans those crazy methodists they
eat
babies what I heard they eat babies stay
stay far away from that church they eat
babies you could you should have you
should read the history of some of the
things that were said about the the
Methodist Church when they came upon the
scene beloved listen this is how the
devil attacks truth the easiest way to
attack truth is to Simply say they eat
babies they're Ault they're crazy
they they require you to stand on your
hand for hours at a time during church
service okay let's forget that one all
right so so so remember what do we have
now beloved there is one article of
furniture left to be restored
[Music]
wow the prophecy the 2300 day prophecy
ends in what year
1844 let me ask you what are the
odds what are the odds are you with me
in your movie what are the odds that God
would bring a movement into existence at
the very end of that time period
1844 what are the odds what are the
odds beloved can I tell you something
you are not a Seventh Day Adventist by
accident you are a movement that has a
prophetic birth
certificate you
arrived oh man a man
can I tell you something there is uh
there was a a football game and you got
to help me out with this cuz I'm
forgetting it now there was a football
game that was played it was Cal State
and Stanton Stanford Stanford and and in
this game there was like uh uh there was
like 3 seconds left on the clock okay
and I believe it was Stanford that was
up in the game and and Cal State they
were about to kick off they they ki they
were going to do a kickoff and the the
the uh band for Stanford thought the
game was over oh yeah all right the the
band came out on the field and they were
marching and playing their music because
they thought the game was
over cal state receives the
ball off they go down the field one
guy's got the ball he's running they
they tackle him and just before he hits
the ground he passes the ball to his
teammate boom number
two number
two off he goes down the field and he's
running and they tackle him but just
before he hits the ground he passes the
ball off to teammate number three now
the commentator as he's speaking his
voice is kind of elevating because he
thinks you know game over but but wait a
minute what's going on
here and Guy number three gets the ball
and off he goes and they tackle him but
just before he hits the ground he passes
it off to guy number
four the fourth guy gets the ball he's
running and they tackle him but just
before he falls he passes off to guy
number
five six guy number
six guy number
six takes it into the the
endzone beloved listen they were all
part of the same
team do you know that Adventists
Adventists are simply Baptists
methodists
Presbyterian laws who took a little of
all the truth that they had and brought
it into one Melting
Pot that's what we were one person
didn't start the Adventist movement it
was started by Baptists and methodists
and Presbyterians and even
Catholics what other movement has that
history now if we were living in
today we would be considered a
cult in fact your neighbors might look
at you funny or those Adventists they
eat babies
you would have to be bold today in order
to say I'm going to stand up and be a
seven day ADV as bold see we can look
back in past say oh Luther Luther I
would have been with you Wesley Wesley I
would have been with you well God says
here's your test
now here's your test now you see beloved
at the at at when 1844 came the Bible
tells us that there is no more time
prophecy in other words words there's no
more time on the clock we are in that
final play of Earth's history beloved
there is no fumbling the ball
now the angels are on their feet looking
with great anticipation seeing are we
going to make it into the end time I
mean the end
zone and so Beloved the people of God
get this ball and off they go down the
field what with the Three Angels
messages fear God and give glory to him
for the what hour of his judgment is
come what is the Judgment based upon
it's based upon the
law do you see Beloved the Judgment
message could not go forward
until the law was
restored so that's why Jesus says when
this gospel shall be preached in all the
world then shall the End come you see
beloved this gospel had been taken away
during the Dark Ages and so it was not
until
1844 when the Full Gospel was restored
that the gospel message could begin to
go forward do you want to know something
the only time the word gospel is
mentioned in the Book of Revelation is
in Revelation 14: 6 and 7 which is the
first Angel's
message wow
it is this gospel that is to go into all
the world and Beloved the truth is a
very simple
one the truth is a very simple one the
gospel that is being preached is very
simple it is get into the
ark okay you didn't get that we'll try
it
again get into the
ark what Ark the Ark of the
Covenant that's the ark that we're
calling people into beloved that's what
we it's Noah's message get in the ark
before it's too
late all right so so we need to see this
very quickly beloved at the same time
that truth is being restored on Earth
something's happening in heaven what is
that it's the Judgment what is a
judgment about who is a judgment
for no the judgment is for the angels in
heaven you see beloved God is trying to
invite Humanity into the Society of
heaven but Angels cannot read the human
heart so when God says so just imagine
with me a person that has lived a life
of just total crookedness and the angels
know it and then on the guy's deathbed
he can't even speak but in his heart he
says Lord forgive
me forgive
me and God says to the angel okay write
his name in The Book of Life the angel
is going like
what okay I will write
it but I know that one day the books
will be opened and you will show all of
us why this guy
saved are you with
me because only God can read the heart
now there is an adver AR and that
adversary is who Satan see God is not
accusing you God doesn't have books to
try to make sure that you're lost like
haha CAU you you're lost God is our
Defender Satan is the prosecutor so when
Satan says look this guy did this this
this this and this the reason why God
has books is because the books contain
evidence that you've
repented God could open a book and say
well according to my books he repented
and that's why he saved
amen are you with me God's judgment is
not against you he's not trying to get
you lost he's he's holding evidence to
save you from Satan's
accusations so by the time this judgment
is over the angels in heaven say just
and true are thy ways oh God are you
with me all right now meantime I'm going
to leave my slides alone now cuz I just
got to like go fast forward we're going
to fast forward okay in the meantime uh
the Three Angels messages go go forward
and those messages are designed to call
our people out of Babylon to not drink
the wine of Babylon the wine of
confusion which says it's okay to ignore
God's law by the way the Bible tells us
it is not fit for Kings to drink wine
lest they drink and forget the
law so that's Proverbs 31:4 and 5 so the
reason we know that the second Angel's
message is directly towards the law of
God is because Babylon is trying to give
the world this cup that makes him say
it's okay to ignore the law of God and
if you have that mentality you will not
be fit for the Kingdom of
Heaven All right so the Three Angels
messages are preached and then what
happens the plagues fall anyone know
where the plagues come
from they come from the most holy
Place why do you think they come from
the most holy Place why are the seven
angels with the seven last plagues seen
coming out of the most holy place it's
very simple because those who receive
the plagues are those who rejected what
was found in the most holy place the law
of God are you with
me
so the plagues are poured out and Jesus
comes I have to show you
this the Bible says we which are we we
which are alive and remain until the
coming of the Lord shall not pre prevent
them which are sleep for the Lord
himself shall descend from heaven with a
shout do you see what article of
furniture is right there the altar of
what sacrifice listen beloved those who
died in Christ and died with him are
going to be what resurrected that altar
right there also points us to th to to
the fact that those that die with him
will also what live with him the labor
what is the labor
about purification do you realize that
no one could enter the temple without
first
washing do you realize that that labor
is pointing us to the to when we get our
new
bodies Our Incorruptible
bodies so the altar of sacrifice those
that die in Christ will be resurrected
the labor when they are resurrected they
will have purified bodies so that they
can
enter the Kingdom of Heaven amen do you
know that seven Branch Candlestick
represents the Kingdom of Heaven
remember a
city set on a hill how many of you
looking forward to entering the New
Jerusalem amen and guess what happens
when we enter the New Jerusalem like we
we don't this is beautiful we don't die
and then just go straight to
heaven we die but we must be resurrected
and purified and then we enter the city
of God even the message of of the state
of the Dead can be found in the
sanctuary so we enter the city of God
and then after we enter the city of God
we get to sit at the welcome
table we get to sit at the welcome table
how many of you looking forward to
sitting at the welcome table amen and
then after we sit at the welcome table
we're going to spend a thousand years
doing
what jewelry
Duty jewelry Duty
we're going to listen what does the
altar of incense represent it represents
Christ's what intercession we're going
to spend a thousand years reviewing
Christ's intercession for the
lost we're going to see how Christ's
intercession for the Lost how it was
rejected by the Lost are you with
me and when that 1,000 years is over
what
happens the Bible says the Bible tells
us that the righteous
at the end of that judgment guess what
we're going to say like the angels in
heaven we too will now say just and what
true are thy ways Thou King of saints do
you see what's happening here the Angels
agree with God redeemed Humanity agrees
with God okay now 1,000 years passes
Jesus and his saints come back down to
earth the wicked are resurrected and
what happens they stand before
what what do they stand
before Revelation 20 says I saw the dead
small and great stand before what the
Throne of
God beloved we're wrapping our movie
up where did the movie
begin Before the Throne of
God where does the movie
End there is Satan and the wicked
standing Before the Throne of
God there they the books are now open to
them and as they themselves review the
books guess what they're going to
say just and true are thy ways oh king
of saints every knee shall bow every
tongue
confess there will be
no there will be a
unanimous
decision that God is
just no one in all the universe will say
oh maybe go no they're going to remember
that the wicked themselves said just and
true are thy ways oh king of
saints you might remember that the Bible
says that Lu Jer would be destroyed from
the midst of the stones of
fire do you know what those stones of
fire
[Music]
were God wrote the law on
Stones Deuteronomy tells us that a fiery
law went forth from his
fingers the very law that Lucifer broke
will destroy
[Music]
him the wicked are burnt
up they become
ashes Christ makes a new Heaven and a
new
Earth and the Bible says in Isaiah 66
from
one
Sabbath to
another All Flesh
will come and worship before
me why because just like Israel
celebrated the
Sabbath as a sign of their deliverance
from
captivity so we will ever keep the
Sabbath in remembrance of our
deliverance from this sinful
[Music]
World Earth's final movie
beloved let us not have the wicked say
to us in the end of time you saw this
movie and you didn't tell me about
it you told me about all these other
movies you saw this movie you didn't
tell me about this
movie you know when the wicked stand
before God Ellen White says it will be
like a panoramic view this world will
turn into the Earth's biggest movie
theater where everyone will see the part
they
played what part will you play in this
movie this is no Make Believe movie
Beloved this is
reality
[Music]
TV the Bible says they that turn many to
righteousness shall shine as the
Stars
forever do you want to be a
star Beloved the place where stars are
born
born the place where Stars Are Born it's
time to be born
[Music]
again beloved I want to I I I'm I
finished I really am the the the end
credits are rolling that's what this and
credits you know
starring starring Jesus
amen but beloved God is wanting to use
you to help lead
others to the way to the throne of God
do you think that you can lead them to
the throne of God God can use you he can
use if it's your desire to be used I
want you to stance your feet and we're
going to
pray Heavenly
Father we thank
you for showing us Earth's final
movie we thank you for giving us an
understanding of the great controversy
and how it all unfolds and how it all
begins and ends before your
throne please Lord help us to watch this
movie again and again help us to hang
the pictures in memory's
Hall that we may easily be able to share
it with those around
us make us Stars Lord
make us
stars in Earth's final movie is our
prayer in Jesus name amen and amen you
may be seated